Guide to the Stanford University Faculty Publications
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University faculty publications
1881-2009
SC4-2499
88 Linear feet
The materials consist of books and assorted pamphlets and reprints of Stanford University faculty.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
The materials consist of books and assorted pamphlets and reprints of Stanford University faculty.
Arrangement note
The materials are arranged in two series: Series 1. Books; Series 2: Pamphlets and reprints.
Collection Contents
- Books, Series 1
  - Abrams, LeRoy, Flora of Los Angeles and Vicinity, 1917 (Box 1)
  - Achilles, Paul S., Psychology at Work; written by various authors, 1932 (Box 41)
  - Adams, Ephraim Douglass, The Influence of Grenville on Pitt's Foreign Policy 1787-1798, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Ephraim Douglass, Great Britain and the American Civil War Vol. 1, 1925 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Ephraim Douglass, Great Britain and the American Civil War Vol. 2, 1925 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Ephraim Douglass, British Interests and Activities in Texas 1838-1846, 1910 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Ephraim Douglass, British Diplomatic Correspondence Concerning the Republic of Texas 1838-1846, 1917 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Ephraim Douglass, The Power of Ideals in American History, 1913 (Box 2)
  - Alden, Raymond Macdonald, Papers 1905-1924 (Box 2)
  - Alden, Raymond Macdonald, Introduction to Poetry, 1909 (Box 2)
  - Alden, Raymond Macdonald, Beaumont's The Knight of the Burning Pestle and A King and No King, 1910 (Box 2)
  - Alden, Raymond Macdonald, English Verse, 1904 (Box 2)
  - Alden, Raymond Macdonald, Essays: English and American, 1918 (Box 2)
  - Alden, Raymond Macdonald, Poems, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Alden, Raymond Macdonald, The Knights of the Silver Shield, 1906 (Box 2)
  - Alden, Raymond Macdonald, Essays: English and American, 1918 (Box 2)
  - Alden, Raymond Macdonald, Poems of the English Race, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Alden, Raymond Macdonald, Readings in English Prose of the Nineteenth Century, 1917 (Box 2)
  - Alden, Raymond Macdonald, The Sonnets of Shakespeare, 1916 (Box 3)
  - Alden, Raymond Macdonald, The Rise of Formal Satire in England Under Classical Influence, 1899 (Box 3)
  - Alighieri, Dante, The Divine Comedy, translated by Melville B. Anderson, 1921 (Box 4)
  - Allen, Clifford G., Fabulas Y Cuentos, 1918 (Box 3)
  - Allen, Clifford G., L'Ancienne Version Espagnole de Kalila et Digna, 1906 (Box 3)
  - Allen, Warren Dwight, Philosophies of Music History, 1939 (Box 3)
  - Almack, John C., Research and Thesis Writing, 1930 (Box 3)
  - Almack, John C., Track of the Sun, 1937 (Box 3)
  - Almack, John C. and Elmer Staffelbach, The Stanford Speller: Grade Two, 1939 (Box 3)
  - Alsberg, C. L., Hearings Before the Committee on Agriculture: Bureau of Chemistry, Estimates of Appropriations for the Fiscal Year Ending June 30, 1915 (Box 3)
  - Anderson, Edward Playfair, The Best Letters of Madame de Sevigne, 1891 (Box 4)
  - Anderson, H. Dewey, Problems in Educational Society by Percy E. Davidson and H. Dewey Anderson. Part One. 1930 (Box 59)
  - Anderson, Melville B., The Happy Teacher, 1910 (Box 4)
  - Anderson, Melville B., Malcom Playfair Anderson, 1919 (Box 6)
  - Baas-Becking, Lourens G. M., Papers 1920-1931 (Box 6)
  - Bailey, Stephen K. et. al., Research Frontiers in Politics and Government:, 1955 (Box 17)
  - Bailey, Thomas A., A Diplomatic History of the American People, 1944 (Box 5)
  - Bailey, Thomas A., The American Spirit: United States History as Seen by Contemporaries, 1963 (Box 7)
  - Bailey, Thomas A., Voices of America, 1976 (Box 7)
  - Bailey, Thomas A.
  - Bailey, Thomas A., Probing America's Past: A Critical Examination of Major Myths and Misconceptions. Volume 1, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Bailey, Thomas A., Probing America's Past: A Critical Examination of Major Myths and Misconceptions. Volume 2, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Baran, Paul A., The Political Economy of Growth; Russian version, 1957 (Box 5)
  - Baran, Paul A., The Political Economy of Growth; Japanese version, 1957 (Box 5)
  - Baran, Paul A., The Political Economy of Growth; Polish version, 1957 (Box 5)
  - Barclay, Thomas S., The Movement for Municipal Home Rule in St. Louis, 1943 (Box 5)
  - Barker, Charles Albro, The Background of the Revolution in Maryland, 1940 (Box 5)
  - Barker, Roger G. and Herbert Wright, One Boy's Day: A Specimen Record of Behavior, 1951 (Box 5)
  - Barnes, Earl, Studies in Education: A Series of Ten Numbers Devoted to Child-Study and the History of Education, 1896-97 (Box 6)
  - Bassett, Lee Emerson, A Handbook of Oral Reading, 1917 (Box 6)
  - Beach, Walter Greenwood and Edward Walker and Olis Jamison, American Democracy and Social Change, 1936 (Box 6)
  - Beach,Walter Greenwood and William Ogburn, An Introduction to Sociology and Social Problems, 1925 (Box 6)
  - Beahan, Willard, The Field Practice of Railway Location, 1904 (Box 6)
  - Bell, Nugent, The Pacific Area and its Problems, 1936 (Box 7)
  - Benavente, Jacinto, El Principe Que Todo Lo Aprendio en Los Libros; introduction by Aurelio Espinosa, 1920 (Box 20)
  - Billings, Frank, Focal Infection: The Lane Medical Lectures, 1916 (Box 7)
  - Bingham, Joseph W., Cases on the Law of Water Rights, 1916 (Box 7)
  - Blackwelder, Eliot and Harlan Barrows, Elements of Geology, 1911 (Box 8)
  - Blichfeldt, H. F., Finite Collineation Groups, 1917 (Box 8)
  - Boezinger, Bruno, Erites Uufakbuch: Nach der Direften Methode, 1915 (Box 8)
  - Boezinger, Bruno, Mundliche und Fchriftliche Ubungen, 1913 (Box 8)
  - Boezinger, Bruno, Zweites Uuffakbuch, 1916 (Box 8)
  - Boissier, Gaston, Madame de Sevigne. translated by Melville B. Anderson, 1888 (Box 4)
  - Bolloten, Bunett, La Revolucion Espanola: Las Izquierdas y la Lucha por el Poder, 1962 (Box 8)
  - Bolloten, Burnett, The Grand Camouflage, 1961 (Box 8)
  - Bolton, Herbert E. and Ephraim Adams, California's Story, 1922 (Box 1)
  - Bowker, Albert H. and Henry Goode, Sampling Inspection by Variables, 1952 (Box 8)
  - Briggs, William D. et. al., Flugel Memorial Volume, 1916 (Box 21)
  - Brown, Charles Reynolds, The Main Points~, 1899 (Box 8)
  - Brown, Charles Reynolds, The Other Seventy, 1903 (Box 8)
  - Brown, Charles Reynolds, Two Parables, 1898 (Box 8)
  - Brown, Charles Reynolds, The Bow in the Cloud, 1907 (Box 9)
  - Brun, Samuel Jacques, Tales of Languedoc, 1896 (Box 9)
  - Burlingame, Leonas L., Podocarpus Araucaria, 1908 (Box 9)
  - Burlingame, Leonas Lancelot, General Biology Laboratory Manual, 1927 (Box 9)
  - Byrd, Oliver E., General Mills Workshop on Administration of School Health Programs, 1949, 1930 (Box 59)
  - Cambell, Douglas H., Elements of Structural and Systematic Botany, 1890 (Box 9)
  - Cambell, Douglas H., A University Text-Book of Botany, 1902 (Box 9)
  - Cannon, Henry L., The Great Roll of the Pipe: For the Twenty-Sixth Year of King Henry III 1241-1242, 1918 (Box 9)
  - Cannon, Henry L., Reading Reerences for English History, 1910 (Box 9)
  - Carruth, William H., Each in His Own Tongue and Other Poems, 1909 (Box 10)
  - Carruth, William H., Each in His Own Tongue, 1920 (Box 10)
  - Carruth, William H., Elementary German Grammar, 1881 (Box 10)
  - Carruth, William H., A German Reader, 1904 (Box 10)
  - Carruth, William H., Letters to American Boys, 1907 (Box 10)
  - Carruth, William H., Kansas in Literature. Pt. 1: Poetry, 1900 (Box 10)
  - Carruth, William H., Kansas in Literature. Pt. 2: Prose, 1900 (Box 10)
  - Carruth, William H., Songs from the Hill (Box 10)
  - Carter, Richard F., Voters and Their Schools. A Technical Report from the Institute for Communication Research, June 30, 1960, 1930 (Box 59)
  - Chenery, Hollis B., The Structure and Growth of the Italian Economy. United States of America Mutual Security Agency, Rome 1953, 1930 (Box 59)
  - Clark, Arthur B., Design: A Text-Book for Students and Craftsworkers, 1915 (Box 11)
  - Clausen, Jens, Stages in the Evolution of Plant Species, 1962 (Box 10)
  - Coester, Alfred, The Literary History of Spanish America, 1916 (Box 11)
  - Coester, Alfred, Historia Literaria de la America Espanola, 1929 (Box 11)
  - Coester, Alfred, Cuentos de la America Espanola, 1920 (Box 11)
  - Coester, Alfred, Anthology of the Modernista Movement in Spanish America, 1924 (Box 11)
  - Coester, Alfred, A Spanish Grammar, 1912 (Box 11)
  - Coester, Alfred, A Year of Spanish, 1930 (Box 12)
  - Coester, Alfred, Revista de las Indias, 1950 (Box 12)
  - Coester, Alfred, A Tentative Bibliography of the Belles-Lettres of the Argentine Republic, 1933 (Box 12)
  - Coman, Edwin T. Jr., Sources of Business Information, 1949 (Box 12)
  - Coover, J. E., Notescript Manual; Notescript Reading Text (2 v.); and Notescript notebook, 1930 (Box 59)
  - Coover, John E., Formal Discipline from the Standpoint of Experimental Psychology, 1912 (Box 11)
  - Coover, John E., Investigation with a "Trumpet" Medium, 1915 (Box 12)
  - Cornill, Carl H., History of the People of Israel, 1909 (Box 10)
  - Cotter, Cornelius P., Government and Private Enterprise, 1960 (Box 12)
  - Cottrell, Edwin A. and Helen Jones, Metropolitan Los Angeles: A Study in Integration. I. Characteristics of the Metropolis, 1952 (Box 12)
  - Cowley, W. H., The Personnel Bibliographical Index, 1932 (Box 12)
  - Crandall, Roderic, The Geology of the San Francisco Peninsula, 1907 (Box 12)
  - Cross, Charles N., Heat Engines, 1930 (Box 13)
  - Cross, Charles N., The Iowa Journal of History and Politics: Vol. 4, Number 4, 1906 (Box 13)
  - Cubberley, Ellwood P., The Fifth Yearbook of the National Society for the Scientific Study of Education, Part II: Certification of Teachers, 1906 (Box 13)
  - Cubberley, Ellwood P., Changing Conceptions of Education, 1909 (Box 13)
  - Cubberley, Ellwood P., Syllabus of Lectures on the History of Education, 1902 (Box 13)
  - Cubberley, Ellwood P., The Improvement of Rural Schools, 1912 (Box 13)
  - Cubberley, Ellwood P., The History of Education, 1920 (Box 13)
  - Cubberley, Ellwood P., An Introduction to the Study of Education, 1925 (Box 13)
  - Cubberley, Ellwood P., The Principal and His School, 1923 (Box 14)
  - Cubberley, Ellwood P., Public Education in the United States: A Study and Interpretation of American Educational History, 1919 (Box 14)
  - Cubberley, Ellwood P., Public Education in the United States: A Study and Interpretation of American Educational History; revised and enlarged editon, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Cubberley, Ellwood P., Public Education in the United States: Readings, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Cubberley, Ellwood P., Public School Administration, 1916 (Box 14)
  - Cubberley, Ellwood P., Public School Administration; revised edition, 1929 (Box 14)
  - Cubberley, Ellwood P., Readings in the History of Education, 1920 (Box 15)
  - Cubberley, Ellwood P., Rural Life and Education, 1914 (Box 15)
  - Cubberley, Ellwood P., School Funds and Their Apportionment, 1906 (Box 15)
  - Cubberley, Ellwood P., School Organization and Administration, 1916 (Box 15)
  - Cubberley, Ellwood P., State and County Educational Reorganization, 1914 (Box 15)
  - Cubberley, Ellwood P., San Francisco Courses of Study, 1900 (Box 15)
  - Cubberley, Ellwood P., State and County School Administration: Source Book, 1915 (Box 16)
  - Cubberley, Ellwood P., State School Administration, 1927 (Box 16)
  - Cutter, Lawrence E., Descriptive Geometry, 1923 (Box 16)
  - Davidson, Percy E., A Source Textbook in American History, 1927 (Box 16)
  - Davidson, Percy E., The Recapitulation Theory and Human Infancy, 1914 (Box 16)
  - Davidson, Percy E., Problems in Educational Society by Percy E. Davidson and H. Dewey Anderson. Part One. 1930 (Box 59)
  - Davis, Joseph S., The Farm Export Debenture Plan, 1929 (Box 16)
  - Davis, Joseph S., Wheat in the World Economy: A Guide to Wheat Studies of the Food Research Institute, 1945 (Box 16)
  - Davis, Joseph S., On Agricultural Policy 1926-1938, 1939 (Box 16)
  - Dawson, Daniel T., Tensions in the Modern Elementary School. Proceedings of the Eleventh National Conference, Department of Elementary School Principals, NAE. 1951, 1930 (Box 59)
  - de LaSalle, Nicolas, Relation of the Discovery of the Mississipi River, translated by Melville B. Anderson, 1898 (Box 4)
  - De Remusat, Paul, Thiers, translated by Melville B. Anderson, 1889 (Box 4)
  - de Tonty, Henri, Relation Concerning the Explorations of LaSalle from 1678 to 1683, translated by Melville B. Anderson, 1898 (Box 4)
  - Dean, Everett S., Progressive Basketball, 1942 (Box 17)
  - Dietrich, Waldemar F., The Clay Resources and the Ceramic Industry of California, 1928 (Box 17)
  - Doane, Rennie W., Insects and Disease, 1910 (Box 17)
  - Doane, Rennie W., Common Pests: How to COntrol Some of the Pests That Affect Man's Health, Happiness and Welfare, 1931 (Box 17)
  - Doane, Rennie W. et. al., Forest Insects: A Textbook for the Use of Students in Forest Schools, Colleges, and Universities, and for Forest Workers, 1936 (Box 17)
  - Dodds, John, Thackeray, 1941 (Box 17)
  - Drew, Elmer R. and Hermon Farwell, Laboratory Experements in Physics, 1924 (Box 17)
  - Dudley, William R., A Catalogue of the Flowering Plants and Vascular Cryptograms, Found In and Near Lackawanna and Wyoming Valleys, 1892 (Box 17)
  - Dudley, William R. and Mason Thomas, A Laboratory Manual of Plant Histology, 1894 (Box 18)
  - Duniway, Clyde A., The Development of Freedom of the Press in Massachusetts, 1906 (Box 18)
  - Duniway, Clyde A., Collected Papers, 1903-1906 (Box 18)
  - Durand, William F., Hydraulics of Pipe Lines, 1921 (Box 18)
  - Durand, William F., Robert Henry Thurston, 1929 (Box 18)
  - Durand, William F., Adventures in the Navy; in Education, Science, Engineering; and in War: A Life Story, 1953 (Box 18)
  - Durand, William F., Addresses After a Dinner Tendered to Edward Dean Adams, 1925 (Box 18)
  - Durand, William F., Researches on the Performance of the Screw Propeller, 1907 (Box 18)
  - Durand, William F., Miscellaneous Papers 1892-1904 (Box 18)
  - Echegaray, Jose, El Gran Galeoto; edited by Aurelio Espinosa, 1918 (Box 20)
  - Eells, Walter C., The Junior College, 1931 (Box 19)
  - Eells, Walter C., Surveys of American Higher Education, 1937 (Box 19)
  - Elliott, Ellen C., The Winds, 1952 (Box 19)
  - Elliott, Ellen C., Other Moons, 1945 (Box 19)
  - Elliott, Ellen C., Footholds in Chaos, 1939 (Box 19)
  - Elliott, Orrin L., Stanford University: The First 25 Years, 1937 (Box 19)
  - Elliott, Orrin L., Stanford University and Thereabouts, 1896 (Box 19)
  - Elliott, Orrin L., The Things That Abide, 1903 (Box 19)
  - Elmore, Jefferson, Book of Latin Prose Composition, 1909 (Box 19)
  - Elmore, Jefferson and Oliver Johnston, A French Grammar for High Schools and Colleges, 1926 (Box 19)
  - Espinosa, Aurelio M., Elementary Spanish Conversation and Composition, 1924 (Box 19)
  - Espinosa, Aurelio M., Advanced Spanish Composition and Conversation, 1932 (Box 20)
  - Espinosa, Aurelio M., Elementary Spanish Reader, 1916 (Box 20)
  - Espinosa, Aurelio M., Espana en Nuevo Mejico, 1937 (Box 20)
  - Espinosa, Aurelio M., Estudios Sorbre el Espanol de Nuevo Mejico, 1930 (Box 20)
  - Espinosa, Aurelio M. and Clifford Allen, Elementary Spanish Grammar, 1915 (Box 20)
  - Espinosa, Aurelio M. and Tomas Navarro, A Primer of Spanish Pronunciation, 1933 (Box 20)
  - Fagen, Elmer D. and C. Macy, Public Finance: Selected Readings, 1934 (Box 20)
  - Farrand, Max, Territory and District, 1900 (Box 20)
  - Fish, J. C. L., Coordinates of Elementary Surveying (Box 60)
  - Fish, J. C. L., Linear Drawing and Lettering (Box 60)
  - Fish, John C. L., Descriptive Geometry, 1903 (Box 20)
  - Fish, John C. L., Earthwork Haul and Overhaul Including Economic Distribution, 1913 (Box 21)
  - Fish, John C. L., Technic of Surveying Instruments and Methods, 1917 (Box 21)
  - Fish, John C. L., Engineering Economics: First Principles, 1915 (Box 21)
  - Fish, John C. L., Engineering Economics: First Principles, Second Edition, 1923 (Box 21)
  - Fish, John C. L., Lettering of Working Drawings, 1894 (Box 21)
  - Fisher, Harold H., America and Russia in the World Community, 1946 (Box 21)
  - Fisher, Walter K., Starfishes of the Philippine Seas and Adjacent Waters, 1919 (Box 21)
  - Fisher, Walter K., Asteroidea of the North Pacific and Adjacent Waters; pt. 1, 1928 (Box 22)
  - Fisher, Walter K., Asteroidea of the North Pacific and Adjacent Waters; pt. 2, 1928 (Box 22)
  - Fisher, Walter K., Asteroidea of the North Pacific and Adjacent Waters; pt. 3, 1928 (Box 22)
  - Franklin, Edward C., The Nitrogen System of Compounds, 1935 (Box 21)
  - Franklin, Edward C., Edward Curtis Franklin; autobiography, 1937 (Box 21)
  - Franklin, Edward C. and J. A. Holmes and Ralph Gould, Report of the Selby Smelter Commission, 1915 (Box 23)
  - Gebhart, Emile, Mystics and Heretics in Italy at the End of the Middle Ages; translated by Edward M. Hulme, 1922 (Box 23)
  - Gerow, Burt A., An Analysis of the University Village Complex, with a Reappraisal of Central California Archaeology (Box 60)
  - Gilbert, Charles H., Age at Maturity of the Pacific Coast Salmon of the Genus Oncorhynchus, 1913 (Box 23)
  - Goebel, Julius, Goethe's Poems, 1904 (Box 23)
  - Goheen, John D., Philosophy and History: Public Lectures at the Seminars in American Studies, University of Tokyo, 1956 (Box 23)
  - Golder, Frank A., John Paul Jones in Russia, 1927 (Box 23)
  - Golder, Frank A., The March of the Mormon Battle, 1928 (Box 24)
  - Grant, Eugene L., Statistical Quality Control, 1946 (Box 24)
  - Grant, Eugene L., Statistical Quality Control; Second Edition, 1950 (Box 24)
  - Grant, Eugene L., Basic Accounting and Cost Accounting, 1956 (Box 24)
  - Grant, Eugene L., Basic Accounting and Cost Accounting; Third Edition, 1964 (Box 25)
  - Grant, Eugene L. and Lawrance F. Bell, Basic Accounting and Cost Accounting; Second Edition, 1964 (Box 24)
  - Grant, Eugene L. and William G. Ireson, Principles of Engineering Economy; Third Edition, 1950 (Box 24)
  - Grant, Eugene L. and William G. Ireson, Principles of Engineering Economy; Fourth Edition, 1960 (Box 24)
  - Grant, Eugene L. and William G. Ireson, Handbook of Industrial Engineering and Management, 1955 (Box 25)
  - Gray, Henry D., Selections from Old Testament Literature, 1930 (Box 25)
  - Greene, Charles W., Papers 1898-1900 (Box 25)
  - Griggs, Edward H., The New Humanism, 1900 (Box 25)
  - Guerard, Albert L., Beyond Hatred, 1925 (Box 25)
  - Guerard, Albert L., France: A Short History, 1946 (Box 25)
  - Guerard, Albert L., France of Tomorrow, 1941 (Box 25)
  - Guerard, Albert L., French Civilization in the Nineteenth Century, 1914 (Box 26)
  - Guerard, Albert L., Napoleon III: A Great Life in Brief, 1955 (Box 26)
  - Guerard, Albert L., Personal Equation: An Autobiography, 1948 (Box 26)
  - Guerard, Albert L., Breve Historia de Francia; translated to Spanish, 1951 (Box 26)
  - Gunkel, Hermann, The Legends of Genesis, 1901 (Box 10)
  - Hall, Howard J., Poems of William Wordsworth, 1924 (Box 26)
  - Hall, Howard J., New Englands Memorial; written by Nathaniel Norton, 1937 (Box 26)
  - Hall, Howard J., Benjamin Tompson 1642-1714: First Native-Born Poet of America, 1924 (Box 26)
  - Hall, Howard J. and John R. Moore, Types of Poetry: Exclusive of the Drama, 1931 (Box 26)
  - Hand, Harold C., Campus Activities, 1938 (Box 27)
  - Hanna, Paul R. et. al., Geography in the Teaching of Social Studies: Concepts and Skills, 1966 (Box 27)
  - Hansen, Hazel D., Early Civilization in Thessaly, 1933 (Box 27)
  - Harcourt, Robert, Electric Arc Welding (Box 60)
  - Harcourt, Robert, Oxy-Acetylene Welding and Cutting (Box 60)
  - Harcourt, Robert H., Elementary Forge Practice: A Textbook for Technical and Vocational Schools, 1917 (Box 27)
  - Hardy, Irene, Poems, 1902 (Box 27)
  - Harman, Willis W., Principles of the Statistical Theory of Communication, 1963 (Box 27)
  - Herriot, John G., Methods of Mathematical Analysis and Computation, 1963 (Box 30)
  - Heyfe, Paul, Die Blinden; analyzed by William H. Carruth, 1905 (Box 10)
  - Hilgard, Ernest R., Air Training Command: Instructions Journal, 1952 (Box 27)
  - Hilgard, Ernest R., Theories of Learning, 1948 (Box 27)
  - Hilgard, Ernest R. et. al., Community Planning for Peacetime Living, 1946 (Box 27)
  - Hoover, Theodore, Mildred Crew Brooke (Box 60)
  - Hoover, Theodore J., Concentrating Ores by Flotation, 1914 (Box 27)
  - Hoskins, L. M., A Text-Book on Hydraulics; second edition, 1911 (Box 27)
  - Hoskins, L. M., The Elements of Graphic Statistics, 1892 (Box 28)
  - Hoskins, L. M., A Text-Book on Hydraulics, 1906 (Box 28)
  - Howard, George E., The American University and the American Man, 1893 (Box 28)
  - Hudson, William H., Studies in Interpretation, 1896 (Box 28)
  - Hudson, William H., The Sphinx and Other Poems, 1900 (Box 28)
  - Hudson, William H., Idle Hours in a Library, 1897 (Box 28)
  - Hudson, William H., The Vicar of Wakefield; written by Oliver Goldsmith, 1909 (Box 28)
  - Hugo, Victor, William Shakespeare, translated by Melville B. Anderson, 1887 (Box 5)
  - Hulme, Edward M., Wandering in France, 1941 (Box 28)
  - Hulme, Edward M., The Middle Ages, 1929 (Box 28)
  - Hulme, Edward M., A History of the British People, 1924 (Box 29)
  - Hulme, Edward M., At Twilight, 1897 (Box 29)
  - Huntington, Tuley F., L'Allegro, Il Penseroso, Comus and Lycidas; written by John Milton, 1900 (Box 29)
  - Hurd, Paul D., Biological Education in American Secondary Schools 1890-1960, 1961 (Box 29)
  - Huston, Charles Andrews, Harvard Studies in Jurisprudence, Vol. 1: The Enforcement of Decrees in Equity, 1915 (Box 29)
  - Ichihashi, Yamato, Japnese Immigration: Its Status in California, 1915 (Box 29)
  - Ilyin, Boris, Green Boundary, 1949 (Box 29)
  - Jackson, J. Hugh et. al., Bookkeeping and Business Knowledge: First-Year Course, 1928 (Box 29)
  - Jackson, J. Hugh et. al., Bookkeeping and Business Knowledge: Second-Year Course, 1926 (Box 29)
  - Jenkins, Oliver P., Primary Lessons in Human Physiology and Health, 1906 (Box 29)
  - Jenkins, Oliver P., Advanced Lessons in Human Physiology, 1891 (Box 29)
  - Jenkins, Oliver P., Primary Lessons in Human Physiology, 1891 (Box 30)
  - Jenkins, Oliver P., Papers 1891-1910 (Box 30)
  - Jenkins, Oliver P., Interesting Neighbors, 1922 (Box 30)
  - Johnson, Francis R., Astronomical Thought in Renaissance England: A Study of the English Scientific Wrightings from 1500 to 1645, 1937 (Box 30)
  - Johnston, Oliver M., The Measure of a Man, 1947 (Box 30)
  - Johnston, Oliver M. and Jefferson Elmore, A French Grammar for High Schools and Colleges, 1926 (Box 30)
  - Jones, Eliot, Harvard Economic Studies, Vol. 11: The Anthracite Coal Combination in the United States, 1914 (Box 30)
  - Jones, Eliot, Principles of Railway Transportation, 1924 (Box 31)
  - Jones, Eliot, The Trust Problem in the United States, 1921 (Box 31)
  - Jones, Helen L., Metropolitan Los Angeles: Its Governments, 1949 (Box 12)
  - Jordan, David S. and Barton Evermann, A Check-List of the Fishes and Fish-like Vertebrates of North and Middle America, 1896 (Box 20)
  - Jordan, David S. and Barton W. Evermann and Charles H. Gilbert, The Aquatic Resources of the Hawaiian Islands, 1905 (Box 23)
  - Jordan, David Starr, The Days of a Man; Vol. 1, 1851-1899, 1922 (Box 31)
  - Jordan, David Starr, The Days of a Man; Vol. 2, 1900-1921, 1922 (Box 31)
  - Kaulfers, Walter Vincent, Modern Languages for Modern Schools, 1942 (Box 31)
  - Kaulfers, Walter Vincent, Four Studies in Teaching Grammar from the Socio-Psychological Viewpoint, 1945 (Box 31)
  - Keen, A. Myra, Check List of California Tertiary Marine Mollusca, 1944 (Box 31)
  - Keesing, Felix M., Modern Samoa (Box 32)